zaonce.net 2015-03-15

# Privacy Policy

### 1\. SCOPE

The practices described in this statement apply to information gathered through our online game _Elite: Dangerous_ (the 'Game') and our website [www.elitedangerous.com](http://www.elitedangerous.com/) (collectively the 'Site') and do not necessarily reflect our practices with respect to information gathered off-line.

The Website is operated by Frontier Developments ('Frontier', 'we', or 'us').   
We comply with data protection legislation such as the Data Protection Act 1998. This regulates the processing of personal data relating to you and grants you various rights in respect of your personal data.

The aim of this statement is to tell you how we will use any personal data you provide through the Site. Please read it carefully before you proceed.

### 2\. WHAT INFORMATION DO WE COLLECT?

We collect the personal data that you provide when you create an account with the Site, download or register to use the Game, play the Game, post material including short audio clips, comment on our public forums or message boards, send direct messages to other players while playing online, or request or purchase other services from us. This personal data includes your:

  * name, address, phone number and email address; and
  * gameplay data including your Game achievements, Game scores and performance, IP address, MAC address or other device ID, other device use information, or other information and statistics regarding your usage of the Game.

In addition, we may collect information when you enter a competition or promotion, or report a problem with the Site.  
You may choose to provide voluntary information as part of a submission to the Site or Game.We also collect information on the pages of the Site which you visit, IP addresses, the type of browser you use and the times you access the Site. However, this information is aggregated and is not used to identify you.

The Site (including the Game (as defined in the EULA) may incorporate technology (which may be provided by Frontier or third party service providers engaged by Frontier (each a "Dynamic Advertising Provider")) which enables advertising to be displayed in the Game on your device, and changed while the Game is being played online. In order that the Dynamic Advertising Provider is able to direct advertising appropriate to your Game and geographic region, as well as to the correct location within the Game, certain non-personally identifiable data and information may be retrieved and retained by the Dynamic Advertising Provider including your IP address, geographic location, in-game position, and information concerning the appearance of advertising visible during your gameplay (for example, the length of time an item of advertising was visible and the dimensions of the advertisements). In addition, the Dynamic Advertising Provider may assign a unique identification number which is stored on your device and which is used to monitor and calculate the number of views of dynamic advertising during gameplay. None of the information collected for this purpose including the identification number can be used to identify you.

Where a Game incorporates dynamic advertising technology, the technology which serves the provision of dynamic in-game advertising is integrated within the Game.

### 3\. HOW WILL INFORMATION ABOUT YOU BE USED AND SHARED?

The information we collect allows us to: 

  * provide the products and services you have ordered;
  * verify your identity and details of your payment method or credit card amount;
  * administer our Site and/or Game and provide customer services;
  * meet legal, regulatory and compliance requirements;
  * monitor and analyse the use of any account to prevent, investigate and/or report fraud, terrorism, misrepresentation, security incidents or crime
  * gather management information to form statistical and trend analysis;
  * communicate with you;
  * investigate any complaints about the Site and/or Game;
  * personalize your experience of the Site and/or Game.

We may employ the services of a third party to help us in certain areas, including without limitation website hosting, maintenance, problem solving, call centre operation. In some cases the third party may receive your information. However, at all times, we will control and be responsible for the use of your information.

We may use aggregated information so we can administer and improve our website and/or Game, analyse trends, gather broad demographic information and detect suspicious or fraudulent transactions. We may pass this information to third parties.  
If you provide a credit or debit card, we may also use third parties to check the validity of the sort code, account number and card number you submit in order to prevent fraud.

If false or inaccurate information is provided and fraud is identified, details will be passed to fraud prevention agencies. Law enforcement agencies may access and use this information. We and other organisations may also access and use this information to prevent fraud and money laundering, for example when:

  * checking details in applications for credit and credit related or other facilities;
  * managing credit and credit related accounts or facilities;
  * recovering debt;
  * checking details on proposals and claims for all types of insurance; and
  * checking details of job applicants and employees.

Please email privacypolicy@frontier.co.uk if you want to have details of those credit reference or fraud prevention agencies from whom we obtain and to whom we pass information about you. 

### 4\. TRANSFER OF YOUR INFORMATION OUTSIDE THE EU

We may transfer some of your information outside of the European Union (the 'EU') to the United States of America and other countries outside of the European Economic Area for the purposes set out in this statement. Some of these countries may not have equivalent data protection legislation governing the use of your personal information.

We use third-party providers to host and store your data, who comply with the US-EU Safe Harbour Framework as set forth by US Department of Commerce regarding the collection, use and retention of Personal data from European Union member countries. These providers have certified their adherence to the Safe Harbour Privacy Principles of notice, choice, onward transfer, security, data transfer integrity, access and enforcement. To learn more about the Safe Harbour programme, please visit <http://export.gov/safeharbour/>.

### 5\. MARKETING COMMUNICATIONS

We will keep you up to date with details of our products and services using the information that you have supplied if you have given permission for this when you registered. You can change your preferences by clicking on the provided link at the end of email communications.

### 6\. COOKIES AND RELATED TRACKING TECHNOLOGIES

Visiting our website(s) with your browser settings adjusted to accept cookies tells us that you want to use Frontier Developments' products and services and that you consent to our use of cookies and other technologies to provide them to you as described in this policy.

#### 6.1 Use of Cookies on our website

We use cookies to collect information about and to store your online preferences. Cookies are small pieces of information sent by a web server to a web browser which allows the server to uniquely identify the browser on each page.   
We may use the following categories of cookies on our website:

**Strictly Necessary Cookies**

These cookies are essential in order to enable you to move around the website and use its features. Without these cookies, services you have asked for such as remembering your login details or shopping basket items cannot be provided.

**Performance Cookies**

These cookies collect anonymous information on how people use our Site. For example, we use Google Analytics cookies to help us understand how customers arrive at our Site, browse or use our Site and highlight areas where we can improve areas such as navigation, shopping experience and marketing campaigns. The data stored by these cookies never shows personal details from which your individual identity can be established.

**Functionality Cookies**

These cookies remember choices you make such as the country you visit our website from, language and search parameters such as size, colour or product line. These can then be used to provide you with an experience more appropriate to your selections and to make the visits more tailored and pleasant. The information these cookies collect may be anonymised and they cannot track your browsing activity on other websites.

**Targeting Cookies or Advertising Cookies**

These cookies may collect information about your browsing habits in order to make advertising more relevant to you and your interests. They are also used to limit the number of times you see an advert as well as help measure the effectiveness of an advertising campaign. The cookies are usually placed by third party advertising networks. They remember the websites you visit and that information is shared with other parties such as advertisers.

**Social Media Cookies**

These cookies allow you to share what you’ve been doing on the website on social media such as Facebook and Twitter. These cookies are not within our control. Please refer to the respective privacy policies for how their cookies work.  
If you want to delete any cookies that are already on your computer, please refer to the help and support area on your internet browser for instructions on how to locate the file or directory that stores cookies.

Please note that by deleting our cookies or disabling future cookies you may not be able to access certain areas or features of our site. To find out more about cookies please visit: [www.allaboutcookies.org](http://www.allaboutcookies.org/) or see [www.youronlinechoices.eu](http://www.youronlinechoices.eu/) which contains further information about behavioural advertising and online privacy.

#### 6.2 Use of Web Beacons.

Some of our Web pages may contain electronic images known as Web beacons (sometimes known as clear gifs) that allow us to count users who have visited these pages. Web beacons collect only limited information which including a cookie number, time and date of a page view, and a description of the page on which the Web beacon resides. We may also carry web beacons placed by third party advertisers. These beacons do not carry any personally identifiable information and are only used to track the effectiveness of a particular campaign.

### 7\. CHILDREN

We respect the privacy of children and encourage parents and guardians to take an active role in managing their children's online activities. Some of our products and services are not available for use for children under 18 years old, and we do not knowingly collect personal information from children in connection with those products and services.

### 8\. LINKS

Our Site contains links to other websites over which we have no control. We are not responsible for privacy policies or practices of other websites to which you choose to link from this site. We encourage use to review the privacy policies of those other websites so you can understand how they collect, use and share your information.

### 9\. SECURITY

We have implemented reasonable technical and organisational measures designed to secure your personal information from accidental loss and from unauthorised access, use, alteration or disclosure. However, the Internet is an open system and we cannot guarantee that unauthorised third parties will never be able to defeat those measures or use your personal information for improper purposes.

### 10\. SALE OF THE BUSINESS

In the event that the business is sold or integrated with another business, your details will be disclosed to our advisers and any prospective purchaser’s adviser and will be passed to the new owners of the business.

### 11\. UPDATING YOUR INFORMATION

You may review, correct, update or change your personal information at any time by amending your details online after logging into [My Account](https://store.elitedangerous.com/customer/account/login/). 

If you opted to receive newsletters, commercial emails or other communications from us at the time you registered on this website but subsequently change your mind, you may opt-out by clicking on the provided link at the end of email communications.

### 12\. CHANGES TO OUR PRIVACY POLICY

If our privacy policy changes in any way, we will place an updated version on this page. Regularly reviewing this page ensures that you are always aware of what information we collect, how we use it and under what circumstances, if any, we will share it with other parties.

### 13\. HOW TO CONTACT US

If you have any questions about this statement or your personal information, please contact us at:

Chief Operating Officer  
Frontier Developments plc  
306 Science Park  
Milton Road  
Cambridge  
CB4 0WG  
England, UK

Or by email: privacypolicy@frontier.co.uk
